<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-04T16:17:39+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">There I Travelled</title><subtitle>My experience about the places I travelled. It could be totally random, mental but memorable</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Trekking at Tirupathi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trekking/tirupathi/early-morning/2020/02/22/trek-to-tirumala.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trekking at Tirupathi" /><published>2020-02-22T14:48:02+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-22T14:48:02+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trekking/tirupathi/early-morning/2020/02/22/trek-to-tirumala</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trekking/tirupathi/early-morning/2020/02/22/trek-to-tirumala.html">&lt;p&gt;For long time we (Myself &amp;amp; Archana) were planning a trip to Tirupathi and getting up to Tirumala by walk. I know there is a footpath there, but never dared to try it out. Somehow this time, I got excited about trekking and decided that we should try it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started from Chennai around 5:45 PM in car and booked a hotel room in Tirupathi for 2 days. Reached the hotel around 11 PM and it was slightly far from the city, but reachable place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/images/tirupathi-trek-1/start-trek.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Start of Trek&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn t sleep the whole night, kind of excited about the experience. Got up around 3 AM and reached bus stand around 4 AM. I was kind of shocked to see a huge crowd standing there to get the darshan ticket, and I met 2 - 3 people who said they can buy a darshan ticket for me, as the foot path ticket would already be filled by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/images/tirupathi-trek-1/start.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Steps Board&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we thought of giving a try and reached the start of footpath where they placed a counter saying that 5000 tickets pending still. I was relaxed to see that and started climbing the steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/images/tirupathi-trek-1/steps.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Steps Board&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial 200 steps were okish, after that it started becoming very steep and we started taking lot of breaks. Inspite of the breaks I felt we were progressing much faster compared to our peer footpathers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/images/tirupathi-trek-1/tired.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Steps Board&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached a place Kali Gopuram. Then only we realised that the current number of tickets available for the footpath was drammatically reduced to 300. And by luck we didn t take any long breaks. Finally we stand at the queue and got the darshan ticket with the time mentioned as 7 PM. It was 6 AM in the morning, I was not sure what I am going to do till 7 PM in the evening at Tirumala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/images/tirupathi-trek-1/kaligopuram.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Steps Board&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Kali gopuram, it was flat. In the footpath there were total of 3600 steps and to reach Kali gopuram, it took 1500 steps approx. So I thought only 2000 steps left and it would take another 1 - 1.5 hours to reach tirumala. But I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/images/tirupathi-trek-1/deers.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Steps Board&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventhough the steps are not that steep now, it was very long. After kali gopuram, it took 6 - 7 kms to reach Tirumala. At times, we were walking in the road with the vehicles coming in opposite direction and finally another steep 500 steps. Thats it we reached Tirumala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/images/tirupathi-trek-1/completion.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Steps Board&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;
The time is 8:20 AM. We started around 5 AM and reached Tirumala in 3.5 hours. Comparitively, it was quicker. We had breakfast in Hotel Sarangapani and gone to stand in line by 10 AM itself. We thought it was a waste to wait till 7 PM and then standing in line. Luckily they allowed us inside at 10 AM itself. It seems there is no time constraint there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we had the darshan of Venkatachalapthy and came out around 1 PM. We were so much tired that we took bus and reached Tirupath bus stand. We didn t do anything much that day. Complete rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day morning we started to Padmavathi temple in Alamelu mangapuram, but it was closed for 1.5 hours, they said some pooja is happening. So we left that place, roamed around Tirupathi for sometime and started back to Chennai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/images/tirupathi-trek-1/sunrise.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Steps Board&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;
Early morning oxygen, Sunrise and the trek experience was more memorable. I will plan another trip to Tirumala via foot path.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For long time we (Myself &amp;amp; Archana) were planning a trip to Tirupathi and getting up to Tirumala by walk. I know there is a footpath there, but never dared to try it out. Somehow this time, I got excited about trekking and decided that we should try it out.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conference at Bangalore</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/conference/bangalore/thriller/2014/04/27/conference-at-bangalore-copy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conference at Bangalore" /><published>2014-04-27T14:48:02+05:30</published><updated>2014-04-27T14:48:02+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/conference/bangalore/thriller/2014/04/27/conference-at-bangalore%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/conference/bangalore/thriller/2014/04/27/conference-at-bangalore-copy.html">&lt;p&gt;Note: This post was from 2014 and I had this thought of writing about my trips before 6 years itself. Eventhough that s the only post I had written about my travel experience, it was good memory to read again. So copying it from my wordpress &lt;a href=&quot;https://thereitravelled.wordpress.com/2014/04/27/mobility-conference-bangalore/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is time it had been Bangalore. One of my friend asked me to come there to attend Big Mobility conference, infact I asked him to come to Chennai to attend Paypal hackathon but finally his words got inplace. Its coz I had this long time desire to meet one of my friend s brother who was an enterprenuer also a Tamil fanatic. So its all set and I booked ticket for Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I booked the boarding place as Thiruvanmiyur and at last minute, I changed my mind (coz I could not have reached Thiruvanmiyur on time) and went to board at CMBT (started to CMBT by bike so it would be fast). And I reached the bus stand well before the time, I think I had some 1 hr sparse time (Also informed the contact person (point to be noted)). So as usual started reading the book (Ananda Vikatan) and parallely waiting for the bus to reach CMBT. By 11.15 PM a bus passed me with the label National Travels on it, bus didn t look that appealing to me and the bus ticket was Rs. 750. So I thought this could not be my bus and for a safety called the contact number of travels. He got suddenly shocked and asked whether I was still in the bus stand ? On hearing this some wobbly gobbly went inside my stomach and he said the bus is now in Maduravoyal. I got really tensed and asked him to cancel the ticket and reimburse the money (coz after reaching the bus stand even I felt why I have to travel till Bangalore just for a conference, but no other go right ? Coz the ticket is booked). He said if you want, you can take an auto and reach Maduraivoyal. Bus will wait there for you and cut the call abruptly (without waiting for my response). And I thought for about 10 seconds and called him again that I will take an auto now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But attending technical conference and hackathons really boost your moral as a developer (Thanks to NG, he introduced these kind of things to me). And as it did before it boosted my confidence again. This time few people reached out to me (only by seeing my face it seems, coz I was a silent spectator in all these events) that whether I could develop an Android app for them, but really how could I ? (Am at Hello World !!! level). I said lets see if time permits. But learning Android or these technical stuff used to be a butterly smooth things to me before. Had lot of passion for learning How stuff works. And I got this guilty feeling that I didn t get that much exposure to convert that passion to make something beyond Hello World. And seeing the ideas presented there and the demand they have, I think taking Android with little bit seriousness will make out the things. This event struck hardly with 2 things,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don t be hesitant in attending a technical event. (It will give lot of exposure about the technologies, demand that they have)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don t change the boarding place (Imagine at 11 o clock letting the bus passing you, and still standing there hopelessly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yah, I met my friend ‘s brother Bala Sundararaman and its really good to see someone from whom you got inspired.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Note: This post was from 2014 and I had this thought of writing about my trips before 6 years itself. Eventhough that s the only post I had written about my travel experience, it was good memory to read again. So copying it from my wordpress site</summary></entry></feed>